JACO VAN CRANENBURGH

Nationality: Dual British/Dutch Mobile: 07719975115 Email: jacovancr@gmail.com

DOB: 09/08/1996

PERSONAL PROFILE

A well rounded and experienced London based IT professional with over 4 years of experience working directly with clients as a Web Developer in both an employed and freelance capacity.

Skills

- Technical skills: HTML5/CSS, Javascript,
 PHP, Vue.js, C# and SQL
- German Proficiency (B2 Level CEFR)
- Touch Typing at 90 100 WPM

- Good interpersonal skills and communication
- Project Management to deadlines and budget

EDUCATION / QUALIFICATIONS

2014 – 2018, BSc Hons 2:1 Computer Science Degree, University of Portsmouth

Completed a 4-year BSc degree (including 1-year placement) in Computer Science that covers many topics within the computing arena. This covered technical skills through units such as Advanced Programming Concepts and Software Engineering, while also giving a strong theoretical understanding of Computer Science such as Data Structures and Networking. Completing the degree has developed and enhanced my skills in:

- Group work, being able to take charge when needed.
- Conducting research, investigating resources on relevant topics.
- Expressing myself verbally and speaking in front of an audience.
- Working independently on projects and managing my time effectively

2021, Level 1 LTA Tennis Coaching Qualification

Qualified assistant Tennis Coach, with experience working with both adults and children. Good communication and patience required to help players improve their game and have fun at the same time. Tennis is a passion of mine, and this qualification allows me to share this passion with others.

EXPERIENCE

Feb 2021 - Present

- Web Development in a freelance capacity, mostly working with Vue.js. This gave me the time and location flexibility to accomplish the following during this time:
- Learned German, including a 3-month residency in Dresden to take an intensive German language course. Passed the B2 CEFR level test with 93%.
- Acquired the Level 1 LTA Tennis Coaching qualification. Gained experience coaching adults and children.

Web Developer – Absowebly, Sept 2018 – Feb 2021

- Worked alongside an excellent team of web specialists at Absowebly, creating dynamic and custom web solutions to fulfil client requirements.
- Utilised my PHP, JS, HTML5/CSS and SQL skills.
- Worked directly with and managed my own clients to determine their needs, plan and implement effective and budget conscious solutions.
- Communicated with the specialists on our team to ensure good design, marketing and SEO processes are maintained throughout.
- Customer service: ongoing maintenance and support for client issues was a crucial part of the job, both via email, telephone and client meetings.

IT Support – University of Portsmouth, Sept 2017 – June 2018

- General in-person IT Support in various University buildings such as the University Library.
- Helping students to resolve their IT problems, such as printer issues, connectivity, MS application software, user account and loaning hardware.
- Logging and escalating issues appropriately.
- Good customer service and responsiveness was essential to the success of this role, especially when students had strict submission deadlines.

Web Developer - Veritas Technologies, June 2016 - July 2017

- Completed a 13-month placement year as part of my degree at Veritas Technologies.
- Worked as part of an Agile team to build and maintain an internal 'dashboard' website that tracked internal team performance statistics.
- This role included building windows services for data collection, maintaining an ASP.net website, designing, maintaining and deploying databases, and communicating with managers to determine requirements.
- Frequent team meetings and scrum stand-ups allowed me to improve my communications skills and teamwork, especially when working alongside other developers for larger features.
- Utilised and improved my C#, HTML/CSS and JS skills.

OTHER

Other interests and hobbies include tennis, snowboarding, language-learning and hiking. For a more personal insight you can find more about me on my website at jacovan.co.uk

References available upon request.